A Finding Aid to the Linda Nochlin Papers, circa 1876, 1937-2017, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writing Project Files, circa 1876; 1953-2016; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 17 Linear feet Boxes 7-21, 30-31, 33-34, OVs 36-37; 3.72 Gigabytes ER012-ER102
  - Essays, 1953-2012; 4.3; Archival Resource Key
    - "Seurat's Grand Jatte: An Anti-Utopian Allegory," Drafts, 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - "Seurat's Grand Jatte: An Anti-Utopian Allegory," Research, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - "Seurat's Grand Jatte: An Anti-Utopian Allegory," Lecture at Guggenheim Museum, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - "Solnonipsism", 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - "Starting from Scratch: the Beginnings of 'Women and Art'," Drafts and Fragments, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 5 computer files (Folder ER048)
    - "Sylvia Sleigh: Portraits of Women Artists and Writers", 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - "Three Women Artists, Three Versions of the Body: Jenny Saville, Louise Bourgeois and Miwa Yanagi", 2009-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - "Utopia II: To the Utopia Station", 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - "Utopia II: To the Utopia Station," Drafts, 2003; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER049)
    - "Van Gogh, Renouard and the Weavers' Crisis," Draft, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - "Van Gogh, Renouard and the Weavers' Crisis," Draft and Offprint, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - "Van Gogh, Renouard and the Weavers' Crisis," Images, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Van Gogh, Renouard and the Weavers' Crisis," Notes, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Van Gogh, Renouard and the Weavers' Crisis," Research, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Vincent Van Gogh's Parc Voyer d'Argenson in Asnières: Love in a Cold Climate", 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "Why Have There Been No Great Women Artists," German Translation, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Why We Still Need Picasso", 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Why We Still Need Picasso," Drafts, 1998; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER050)
    - "Women at the [Venice] Biennale", 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Women in the 19th Century: Categories and Contradictions, French Translation, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "The World According to Gober", 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Lectures, 1956-2014; 4.4; Archival Resource Key
    Nochlin's lectures deal mainly with gender and feminist issues, as well as the intersection of these issues with race and culture. Other topics include contemporary artists, art criticism, and autobiographical lectures including "Memoirs of an Ad Hoc Art Historian" and "Memoirs of a Radical Art Historian." The location or associated event of each lecture is noted if known.
    - "1848: The Revolution of Theory" at Frick Collection Museum, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "The Academy and the Life and Death of narrative" at J. Wayne Reitz Union, University of Florida, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "Against the Grain: Representing the Working Woman in 19th Century Painting" at Musée d'Orsay and Musée du Louvre, 2000-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Alice Neel Lecture" at Victoria Miro Gallery, London, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Alice Neel Lecture" at Victoria Miro Gallery, London - Draft, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER051)
    - "Art Criticism and Its Enemies" at International Association of Art Critics Distinguished Critic Lecture at The New School, New York, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - "The Art of Destruction/The Destruction of Art" at SVA Symposium, Drafts and Notes, 2002; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 9 computer files (Folder ER052)
    - Art of Jean-Léon Gérôme Lecture at The Getty, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "Body Politics: Seurat's Poseuses and the Problem of the Nude in the late Nineteenth Century," Article Draft Materials, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER053)
    - "Body Politics: Seurat's Poseuses and the Problem of the Nude in the late Nineteenth Century" at Metropolitan Museum of Art, Notes and Outlines, 1991-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "Body Politics: Seurat's Poseuses and the Problem of the Nude in the late Nineteenth Century" at Metropolitan Museum of Art, Typescripts, 1991-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - "Cézanne and the Modern Portrait" at Portraits in Context Seminar at National Portrait Gallery, Australia, 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - "Contemporary Women", 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - "The Dark Side of Bohemia," Fragment of Draft, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Digital Images for Various Lectures, 2002-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Digital Presentations for Various Lectures, 2004-2009; Archival Resource Key; 0.1 Gigabytes 7 computer files (Folder ER054)
    - "Dislocating Tradition: Women Artists and the Body" at Yale University, 2006-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - "Equine Visions: The Horse in the 19th Century", 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - "Equine Visions: The Horse in the 19th Century," Drafts, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER055)
    - Feminist Art History Lecture at Association of Art Historians Conference, England, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - "Géricault, or the Absence of Women" at Louvre Museum, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Géricault, or the Absence of Women" at Louvre Museum, 1991-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - "Géricault, or the Absence of Women" at Louvre Museum, Drafts and Notes, 1991-1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER056)
    - "Géricault, Goya and the Representations of Misery After the Industrial Revolution" at The Prado Museum, 2010-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - "Girodet Talk" at Louvre Museum, 2005; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER054. (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "Girodet Talk" at Louvre Museum, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Holman Hunt's Awakening Conscience and the Theme of the Fallen Woman in the 19th Century," J. Walter Cook Alumni Lecture, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - "Image of the Working Woman" in Frankfurt, Germany, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - "Introduction: Against Methodology: (Confessions) Thoughts of an Ad Hoc Art Historian," Drafts, 1995-1997; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER057)
    - "Manet, Fashion and the Femme Fetale" at Femme Fetale: Fashion and Visual Culture in Fin de Siècle Paris Symposium at Fashion Institute of Technology, 2002-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - "Mary Cassatt, Louisine Havermeyer and Japanese Art" in Frankfurt, Germany, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - "Memoirs of an Ad Hoc Art Historian" at Columbia University, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - "Memoirs of a Radical Art Historian" at Vassar College, 1993-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - "Modes of Silence", 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - "The Museum as Bildungsroman: My Life in Art, Trash and Fashion" at Material Things Conference, Toronto, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - "The Necessity of Criticism" for International Association of Art Critics Conference, New York, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - "New Woman" at International Center of Photography Panel, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Nochlin and Yve-Alain Bois Discussing Matisse and Picasso, 1998; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - "Not Too Far from Brooklyn: Growing Up, Growing Old with Art" for Charles Homer Haskins Prize in Montreal, 2005-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Nudes Now and Then: Women Artists and the Body" at Dahesh Museum Symposium, 2000-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Old Age Lecture, Research, 2003-2006; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER059. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Old Age Lecture, Presentation, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.021 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER059)
    - Old Age Lecture, Typescripts, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Picasso and the Color of Portraiture" at Museum of Modern Art, New York, 1996; Archival Resource Key; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Picasso and the Color of Portraiture" at Museum of Modern Art, New York - Drafts, Outlines, Slide Lists, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 5 computer files (Folder ER060)
    - "Pissarro's Representation of Women" at Pissarro's Politics in Context: Anarchism and the Arts Colloquium at Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Pornography and Political Representation" for Berkshire Conference, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - "Portraiture and the Construction of Modern Identity" at Rutgers University, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - "A Rage to Paint: Jean Mitchell and the Issue of 'Femininity'" at College Art Association - Drafts, Outlines, Slide Lists, 1991-2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 14 computer files (Folder ER061)
    - "A Rage to Paint: Jean Mitchell and the Issue of 'Femininity'" at College Art Association, Research, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "A Rage to Paint: Joan Mitchell and the Issue of 'Femininity'" at College Art Association, Typescripts, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Re-Reading Cassatt: An American Woman Painter and Her Contemporaries" at Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "Re-Reading Cassatt: An American Woman Painter and Her Contemporaries" at Metropolitan Museum of Art, Drafts, 1994-1997; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER062)
    - "The Revenge of the Spider: Deconstruction and Innovation in the Work of Women Artists" at Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Romaine Brooks Lecture, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "Self Knowledge" at Vassar College, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - "The Seminar as Bildungsroman: History Personal and Impersonal" at College Art Association, Atlanta, 2004-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "The Seminar as Bildungsroman: History Personal and Impersonal" at College Art Association, Atlanta - Drafts, Abstracts, Session Rosters, 2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 5 computer files (Folder ER063)
    - "Sex and the Sepoy Mutiny: The Intersection of Race and Gender in Colonialist Representation," Drafts and Notes, 1981-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Sex and the Sepoy Mutiny: The Intersection of Race and Gender in Colonialist Representation," Research, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - "The Sketch, Sketchiness and the Effect of the Aesthetic in 19th Century French Art", 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - "Speaking About Pictures" Blashfield Address at American Academy of Arts and Letters Ceremony, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - "Speaking About Pictures" Blashfield Address at American Academy of Arts and Letters Ceremony, Draft, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER064)
    - "Splendeurs et Miseres de la Pornographie" at Centre Pompidou, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Toulouse-Lautrec and Graphic Work Lecture, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - "Vassar, Art, and Me: Memoirs of a Radical Art Historian," Draft, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER058)
    - "Who's Millennium is it Anyway? Beauty, Truth and Justice at the Fin de Siècle" at Culture and Humanity in the New Millennium Conference in Hong Kong, 1999-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - "Who's Millennium is it Anyway? Beauty, Truth and Justice at the Fin de Siècle" at Culture and Humanity in the New Millennium Conference in Hong Kong, Drafts, 2000-2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 6 computer files (Folder ER065)
    - "Why the 1860s is the Best Decade in the Nineteenth Century - or Any Other", 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - "Why the 1860s is the Best Decade in the Nineteenth Century - or Any Other," Drafts, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER066)
    - "Why Contemporary Art is Great: Two Women, One Man" at Vassar College, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - "Why Contemporary Art is Great: Two Women, One Man" at Vassar College, Draft, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER067)
    - "Why Have There Been No Great women Artists - 30 Years After" at Princeton University, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - "Why Have There Been No Great women Artists - 30 Years After," Draft, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER068)
    - "Women, Art and Power", 1985-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - "Women Artists: The Japanese Impulse," Drafts, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - "Women Artists: The Japanese Impulse," Nochlin Interview with Midori Yoshimoto in New York City, September 30, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - "Women Artists: The Japanese Impulse," Research, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - "Women and Public Space" at College Art Association, Chicago, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - "Women and Public Space" at College Art Association, Chicago - Drafts, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER069)
  - Files on Artists, 1968-2016; 4.5; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries consists of typescripts, drafts, lectures, correspondence, and research material that includes printed materials, notes, images of artwork, and other material related to the artist. The folders may contain material for multiple writing projects on an artist. The file for Philip Pearlstein includes a few of Nochlin's diary entries discussing her experience sitting for Pearlstein when he painted Nochlin and Richard Pommer's wedding portrait in 1968.
    - Allfest, Ellen, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Drafts and notes
    - Allfest, Ellen, 2013-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Research material
    - Aptekar, Ken, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Correspondence and interview transcript
    - Aptekar, Ken, 1997-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Aptekar, Ken, 1999-2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 6 computer files (Folder ER070)
    - Bacon, Francis, 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Bacon, Francis, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Baronio, Joyce, 1975-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Baronio, Joyce, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Bechtle, Robert, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Bechtle, Robert, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Benglis, Lynda, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Bernal, Olga, 1996-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Bois, Yve-Alain, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Bourgeois, Louise, circa 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
      Digital prints of artwork
    - Bourgeois, Louise, 2007-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
      Lectures
    - Bourgeois, Louise, 2001-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13)
      Manuscripts and research material
    - Brown, Cecily, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Brown, Milton, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER071)
    - Calle, Sophie, 1992-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Cassatt, Mary, 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16)
      Drafts
    - Cassatt, Mary, 2009; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER054. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Cassatt, Mary, 1999-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 18)
      Manuscripts
    - Diaghilev, Serge, 2009-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 19)
      Correspondence
    - Diaghilev, Serge, circa 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Diaghilev, Serge, 2008-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Diaghilev, Serge, circa 2009; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 37)
    - Downes, Rackstraw, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Francis, Sam, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Frank, Mary, circa 1993-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 24)
      Includes born-digital material, see ER073.
    - Frank, Mary, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Frank, Mary, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER072)
    - Frank, Mary, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Frank, Mary, 1993-2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Frank, Natalie, 2012-2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Frank, Natalie, 2014; Archival Resource Key; 0.302 Gigabytes 183 computer files (Folder ER073)
    - Gilje, Kathleen, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Gober, Robert, 2002-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Gober, Robert, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER074)
    - Graves, Nancy, 1971-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Graves, Nancy, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Guston, Philip, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Harrison, Rachel, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Havemeyer, Louisine Elder, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Hockney, David, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Hockney, David, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Hoffman, Malvina, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Hoffman, Malvina, 1980-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Hoffman, Malvina, circa 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Hopper, Edward, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Kelly, Ellsworth, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Kelly, Ellsworth, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 37)
    - Kelly, Ellsworth, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital materials, see ER075. Transfer not possible for 2 disks. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Kelly, Ellsworth, 1996-1999; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER075)
    - Kollwitz, Käthe, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Kollwitz, Käthe, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER076)
    - Lachaise, Gaston, 2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Lehr, Mira, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Levy, Alphonse, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Lou, Liza, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Lou, Liza, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Lucas, Sarah, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Matisse, Henri, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Matisse, Henri, 1993; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER077)
    - Mitchell, Joan, circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Mitchell, Joan, circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Mitchell, Joan, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 23)
      1 notebook
    - Mitchell, Joan, 1984-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Mitchell, Joan, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Mitelberg, Zuka, 1988-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Mitelberg, Zuka, undated; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER078)
    - Morisot, Berthe, 1987-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Murphy, Catherine, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Neel, Alice, 1969-1983; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 37)
    - Neel, Alice, 1973-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Neel, Alice, 2001-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - O'Keefe, Georgia, 1977-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - O'Keefe, Georgia, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Opie, Catherine, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Pearlstein, Philip, 1968-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 32)
      Includes diary entries written by Nochlin during her sittings for Pearlstein's portrait of her and Richard Pommer.
    - Pearlstein, Philip, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 37)
    - Pearlstein, Philip, 1993; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER079)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Rebay, Hilla, circa 2014; Archival Resource Key; Includes born-digital records, see ER054. (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Renoir, 1985-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Renoir, 2007-2008; Archival Resource Key; 0.105 Gigabytes 41 computer files (Folder ER080)
    - Rosenblum, Robert, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Roth, Moira, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Sargent, Margarett, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Sargent, Margarett, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER081)
    - Saville, Jenny, 1999-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Saville, Jenny, 2002-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER082)
    - Saville, Jenny, 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Segal, George, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Sharrer, Honore, 2001; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER083)
    - Sharrer, Honoré, 2001-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Simonds, Charles, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Includes born-digital materials, see ER084.
    - Simonds, Charles, 2013; Archival Resource Key; 2.22 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER084)
    - Sleigh, Sylvia, 2008; Archival Resource Key; 0.03 Gigabytes 319 computer files (Folder ER085)
    - Sleigh, Sylvia, 1985-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Smith, Kiki, 2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER086)
    - Smith, Kiki, 2004-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 10)